Finding Aid of the UW-Milwaukee Dept. of Social Work Records, 1982-2012
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
UW-Milwaukee Dept. of Social Work Records, 1982-2012
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee. Dept. of Social Work
UWM Archival Collection 203
Accession 2015-017
7 cubic ft. (7 boxes) plus additions of 1.4 cubic ft. (2 boxes)
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
Syllabi files from the Department of Social Work, dating from 1982 to 2012. The Department, which is one of two in the Helen Bader School of Social Welfare, maintained these central files of course syllabi per the UW-Milwaukee Uniform Syllabus Policy. The syllabi include information on departmental policies, course schedules, course readings, and information on teaching faculty. The collection also includes additions of restricted executive committee meeting minutes, dating from 1995 to 2000.
In 1956, when the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee was established, the Department of Social Work was created, and administered within the College of Letters & Science. In April 1963, the School of Social Work was established, headed by a director, and remained part of the College of Letters & Science. In 1965, the School changed its name to the School of Social Welfare and became an independent, dean-headed school. The School of Social Welfare during this period maintained a curriculum similar to that of the modern Department of Social Work, although in 1968 a program in Criminal Justice was added to the school's offerings. In 2002, the faculty of the School of Social Welfare voted to departmentalize the school into a Department of Criminal Justice and a Department of Social Work, citing the need for both programs to focus on their particular specialities. The split was approved by the Faculty Senate and the two departments split in Spring 2003.
Department Heads
1956-1957 Willard E. Downing
1957-63 John W. Teter
1963-1968 Quentin F. Schenk
1969-1972 P. Frederick Delli Quadri
1973-1974 John W. Teter
1974-1979 Gregory O'Brien
1980-1988 Fred Cox
1988-1989 William Berg
1989-1991 James Blackburn
1991-1994 Robert Scheurell
1994-1995 Sharon Keigher
1995-1997 William Berg
1997-2002 Joan Jones
2002-2004 James A. Blackburn
2004- Deborah Padgett
The majority of the collection contains course syllabi from courses offered by the Department between 1982 and 2012. Accession 2015-017 includes restricted executive committee meeting minutes from 1995 to 2000. These minutes include decisions made on tenure and promotion, and other sensitive matters pertaining to the department.
UWM Archival Collection 203: UW-Milwaukee Dept. of Social Work Records, Records, 1982-2012
The syllabi files are organized chronologically, then by course number.
The collection contains one additional accession:
Accession 2015-017: Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1995-2000
Related Material in the UWM Libraries
UW-Milwaukee School of Social Welfare, Office of the Dean Records UWM Archival Collection 24
UW-Milwaukee School of Social Welfare, Office of the Associate Dean Records UWM Archival Collection 133
John W. Teter Papers UWM Manuscript Collection 49
Administrative/Restriction Information
The executive committee records in accession 2015-017 are restricted in accordance with UWM Personnel File Policy S-42. Access is regulated by Section III.A.2 and III.A.3.
There are no access restrictions on the rest of the collection, which is open to all members of the public in accordance with state law.
The Department of Social Work donated accession 2007-042 in April 2008. Additional accessions of syllabi files were transferred in March 2013 (accession 2012-047) and August 2014 (accession 2014-018). The executive committee records (accession 2015-017) were transferred to the archives in October 2015.
Contents List
- UW-Milwaukee Department of Social Work Records, 1982-2012, UWM Archival Collection 203; 7 cubic ft. (7 boxes)
  - Syllabi
    - 1982-1986 (Box 1)
    - 1987-1991 (Box 2)
    - 1992-1996 (Box 3)
    - 1996-2000 (Box 4)
    - 2001-2004 (Box 5)
    - 2004-2008 (Box 6)
    - 2008-2012 (Box 7)
- Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1995-2000, Accession 2015-017; 1.4 cubic ft. (2 boxes); Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1995-2000. Includes decisions made on tenure and promotion and other sensitive matters pertaining to the operation of the department. Minutes of meetings discussing consideration of faculty tenure include closed-session discussion of personnel actions and decisions, merit review scores, and course evaluation summaries.
  The accession is restricted under UWM Select Policy S-42 (Personnel File Policy), as well as the closed meeting session provisions in Wis. Stat. 19.85 (c). Consult an archivist for additional information.